## Ricky Garcia

South Jordan, UT 🏫

3854167996

Rg3646@outlook.com

linkedin.com/in/ricky-g-garcia in

Senior Software Engineer with a focus on front-end development, experienced in agile collaboration, and dedicated to continuous learning and professional growth. Demonstrates a strong track record of delivering high-quality software solutions that meet user and stakeholder needs.

### **Skills**

### **Development Languages**

- TypeScript
- JavaScript
- SCSS
- C#

### Frameworks & Libraries

- React.js
- .Net
- Material UI
- Ant Design
- Bootstrap

#### **Tools & Platforms**

- AWS
- Azure
- Webpack
- GitHub
- Jest

### **Experience**

2/2022 - 3/2023

### Senior Software Engineer / Vyne Dental

- Worked on Vyne Trellis, the hub for the dental billing software, developing new features and enhancing existing ones using React, TypeScript, Ant Design, Azure, and AWS.
- Reduced technical debt by identifying areas for improvement, creating tickets for work to be done, and refactoring old JavaScript code to TypeScript.
- Separated spaghetti code into modular components and code, resulting in a cleaner and more maintainable codebase.
- Mentored junior developers, fostering a collaborative and supportive learning environment within the team.

### Senior Software Engineer / Purple

- Worked on promotions and sales for Purple products, including mattresses, bedding, and apparel, on their live customer-facing website, playing a key role in high-traffic periods like Black Friday and Christmas.
- Increased sales revenue through successful promotions and improved developer and user experience by adding features to enhance UX, such as redesigning the pre-checkout cart.
- Collaborated with Promotions, Design, Product, QA, and Project Management teams in an agile environment, participating in daily standups, sprints, and handoffs to ensure seamless coordination.
- Utilized technologies such as JavaScript, SCSS, Vue.js, and Craft CMS to create and implement frontend content for both new and existing products.

9/2019 - 2/2021

### **Software Engineer/ CardWorks**

- Worked on the internal ticketing system, an essential application for tracking activity and streamlining workflows for Data Analysts.
- Maintained and improved the user experience of the site by refining the front-end interface and optimizing performance.
- Collaborated closely with the Data Analyst team, ensuring that their needs and requirements were met while continuously enhancing the application.
- Utilized technologies such as Angular, .Net, C#, TypeScript, MSSQL Server, and SCSS to deliver a robust and efficient solution.

12/2018 - 06/2019

# Front End Developer II/ Melaleuca: The Wellness Company

- Collaborated closely with cross-functional teams to deliver exceptional user experiences for product pages and micro-sites.
- Worked in an agile environment, partnering with backend developers to deliver comprehensive solutions that met business requirements.
- Developed and launched new features, as well as maintained existing codebases.
- Utilized C#, SCSS, Agile Methodologies, JavaScript, React.js, and HTML to deliver high-quality code

### Frontend Web Producer (Contract)/ Micron Technology

- Created visually appealing designs for Micron Consumer Products Group's domestic, regional, and international sites.
- Identified and addressed site issues with workable solutions within strict time constraints, collaborating with multiple departments and time zones to produce desired outcomes.
- Operated Content Management Systems and eCommerce tools for site production.
- Utilized Adobe Experience Manager (AEM), Jira, Agile Methodologies, JavaScript, and Cascading Style Sheets (CSS) to deliver high-quality work.

02/2017 - 07/2018

## Web Designer and Developer/ RS&I

- Led the redesign of the customer-facing website and HubSpot blog, playing a key role in web design and development.
- Optimized website performance by creating custom solutions and landing pages and designed engaging email templates aligned with company branding.
- Restructured the web leads funnel for improved lead generation and customer experience.
- Optimized website performance by creating custom solutions and landing pages and designed engaging email templates aligned with company branding.
- Restructured the web leads funnel for improved lead generation and customer experience.

### **Education**

MAY 2014

### Bachelor's Degree, Economics / Idaho State University

Gained a deep understanding of market dynamics and principles of business and marketing.

### **Certifications**

JAN 2023

## **AWS Certified DevOps – Professional**

Demonstrated proficiency DevOps in cloud-based environment using AWS.

OCT 2022

### **AWS Certified Developer – Associate**

Demonstrated proficiency in developing, deploying, and debugging cloud-based applications using AWS.